<!-- Event Stuff for EMV Woohoo -->

<eventList name="ITEMS_EMV_MVPMC">
	<event load="EMV_MVPMC_RETIREMENT"/> <!-- Retirment guy -->
	<event load="EMV_MVPMC_BADASSITUDE"/> <!-- holy shit is that a borderlands reference -->
	<event load="EMV_MVPMC_CONSPIRACY"/> <!-- Conspiracist -->
    <event load="EMV_MVPMC_FREIGHTER" /> <!-- Destroyed Freighter -->
    <event load="EMV_MVPMC_GRADUATION"/> <!-- Graduation party -->
</eventList>

<eventList name="NEUTRAL_EMV_MVPMC">
	<event load="EMV_MVPMC_UNAUTHORIZED"/> <!-- Unauthorized individual -->
	<event load="EMV_MVPMC_PROPAGANDA"/> <!-- Propaganda event -->
	<event load="EMV_MVPMC_SCRAPYARD"/> <!-- The Scrapyard event-->
	<event load="EMV_MVPMC_PREY"/> <!-- Psychotic bounty hunter-->
    <event load="EMV_ROGUE_CAMP_SEARCH"/> <!-- oh my god its a future content ?!-->
	<event load="EMV_MVPMC_CONVOY"/> <!-- Nothin' happens -->
	<event load="EMV_MVPMC_ENVY"/> <!-- Nothin' happens, also borderlands woa -->
</eventList>

<eventList name="DISTRESS_EMV_MVPMC">
	<event load="EMV_MVPMC_FUEL_DISTRESS"/> <!-- Fuel guy -->
</eventList>

<eventList name="QUESTS_EMV_MVPMC">
	<event load="EMV_MVPMC_SHERIFF"/> <!-- Sheriff questline (holy shit it is long)-->
</eventList>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_FUEL_DISTRESS" unique="true">
    <ship load="SHIP_MULTIVERSE_TRAVELER"/>
    <text>You track down the distress beacon, only to barely graze the hull of the ship transmitting it as you exit lightspeed. You get your bearings and establish contact with the ship.

"Hello uhhh, can you help? We underestimated how much fuel we needed for this journey and well... we don't have any fuel so care for a little charity?"</text>
    <choice>
        <text>Give them some fuel.</text>
        <event>
            <text>You offer the Renegade a few fuel cells and wish them good luck on their journey. Before you depart, they hail you.

"Hey, thanks for the help. I figured you could use this as you go, you need it more than i do. Good luck, captain."
The Renegade offers to install a weapon they had on your ship as a returned favour for your help.</text>
            <item_modify>
                <item type="fuel" min="-5" max="-7"/>
            </item_modify>
            <autoReward level="LOW">weapon</autoReward>
        </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
        <text>Say that you also don't have much fuel but give them one cell.</text>
        <event>
            <text>You explain to the Renegade that you're also running out of fuel and can barely make it to the nearest beacon, but you still give them one fuel cell and wish them good luck.
                
"Well... I won't act like a beggar, this is better than nothing. At least you weren't like those pricks who have a lot of fuel but hide it. Here, take this, I don't take something for nothing."</text>
            <item_modify>
                <item type="fuel" min="-1" max="-1"/>
            </item_modify>
            <autoReward level="LOW">scrap_only</autoReward>
        </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
        <text>Close communications and open fire.</text>
        <event>
            <text>Upon hearing the request you cut communications, only to be hailed again as the ship picks up speed towards you.

"OH NOW YOU'RE VALUING A SINGLE FUEL CELL OVER A LIFE!? I'LL SHOW YOU HOW PRECIOUS LIFE IS BY KILLING YOU!"</text>
			<ship hostile="true"/>
			<choice hidden="true">
				<text>Continue...</text>
				<event load="MORALITY_UPDATE_EMV_RENEGADES_FIGHT"/>
			</choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
    <!--
    <choice>
        <text>Give them a lot of fuel.</text>
    </choice>-->
    <choice>
        <text>Apologize profusely and run away.</text>
        <event>
            <text>You leave the stranded renegade profoundly confused as you apologize and leave.</text>
    		<choice>
				<text>Do something onboard the ship.</text>
				<event load="STORAGE_CHECK"/>
			</choice>
			<choice>
				<text>Get away from the awkward situation as quickly as possible.</text>
				<event/>
			</choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
</event>    

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_UNAUTHORIZED" unique="true">
    <text>Through the corner of your eye, you see two ships in the distance with their weapons armed. This is unusual since it is strictly forbidden for MVPMC Renegades to draw their weapons against each other here. However, upon closer inspection, it turns out one of them is a Renegade, while the other is a Union vessel.</text>
    <choice>
        <text>Tap into the frequency.</text>
        <event>
            <text>You adjust your radio to tune into the frequency to see what's going on.
                
"Okay, how did you even get here? There is absolutely no way you made this on your own, who let you in?"

"That's none of your business. I live in this sector, my home is literally here!"

"Wha- wh- why-... Okay, listen to me. I'll make this simple, if you let me reroute you to somewhere else, without any resistance, I can pretend none of this had happened."

"Nuh uh."

"What? What do you mean "nuh uh?" "

"I'm not coming with you."

"Oh for the love of whatever people pray to just- wait, how long have you been standing ther- actually, can you kill this unauthorised thing? I'll make it worthwhile, just please make my life easier."

"Wait, no no no no this won't do, you're not gonna listen to him are you? I'm just a civilian, you can't just kill me!"

"Uh, yes they can? And like, last time I checked, civilians don't live here?"

"Please, you can't kill me for saying the truth!"</text>
            <choice>
                <text>Attack the Union Vessel.</text>
                <event>
                    <ship load="SHIP_EMV_MVPMC_UNION_UNAUTHORIZED" hostile="true"/>
                    <text>You decide to uphold the rules and get rid of the unauthorised personell from this space. "No! You can't do this to me!" Prepare to fight!</text>
                    <choice>
                        <text>Continue...</text>
                        <event load="MORALITY_UPDATE_UNION_FIGHT"/>
                    </choice>
                </event>
            </choice>
            <choice>
                <text>Attack the Renegade.</text>
                <event>
                    <ship load="SHIP_EMV_MVPMC_GUARD_UNAUTHORIZED" hostile="true"/>
                    <text>As you arm your weapons, the Renegade hails you in disbelief. "WELL, AS IF MY DAY DOESN'T GET ANY WORSE! WE HAVE AN ACTIVIST PROTECTING CIVILIANS! PREPARE THE BATTLE STATIONS!"</text>
                    <choice>
                        <text>Continue...</text>
                        <event load="MORALITY_UPDATE_EMV_RENEGADES_FIGHT"/>
                    </choice>
                </event>
            </choice>
            <choice>
                <text>Let them handle it on their own.</text>
                <event>
                    <text>"What? OH NOW SUDDENLY YOU GAIN MORALITY? Jeez, why does everyone feel the need of getting soft on me-" You close the comms and prepare to jump away before the situation gets more heated with your presence.</text>
                    <choice>
                        <text>Do something onboard the ship.</text>
                        <event load="STORAGE_CHECK"/>
                    </choice>
                    <choice>
                        <text>Do nothing..</text>
                        <event/>
                    </choice>
                </event>
            </choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
        <text>Let them have it at each.</text>
        <event>
            <text>Whatever is going on with these two, it doesn't concern you. You leave before the situation gets ugly and for whatever reason decides that you're part of it. You ready the engines for a jump.</text>
    		<choice>
				<text>Do something onboard the ship.</text>
				<event load="STORAGE_CHECK"/>
			</choice>
			<choice>
				<text>Do nothing..</text>
				<event/>
			</choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
</event>

<ship name="SHIP_EMV_MVPMC_UNION_UNAUTHORIZED" auto_blueprint="LIST_SHIPS_UNION_FIGHT">
	<destroyed load="EMV_DESTROYED_UNION_UNAUTHORIZED"/>
	<deadCrew load="EMV_DEADCREW_UNION_UNAUTHORIZED"/>
	<crew>
		<crewMember type="human" prop="0.80"/>
		<crewMember type="LIST_CREW_UNION_RANDOM" prop="0.20"/>	
	</crew>
</ship>

<ship name="SHIP_EMV_MVPMC_GUARD_UNAUTHORIZED" auto_blueprint="LIST_MULTIVERSE_TRAVELERS">
	<destroyed load="EMV_DEFEAT_GUARD_UNAUTHORIZED"/>
	<deadCrew load="EMV_DEFEAT_GUARD_UNAUTHORIZED"/>
</ship>


<event name="EMV_DESTROYED_UNION_UNAUTHORIZED">
    <text>The civilian vessel has been vanquished. You doubt that this would look good on your record though, plenty of scrap to be earned on the other hand..</text>
	<autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
    <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Continue...</text>
        <event>
            <text>The Renegade vessel hails you once more. "About time someone decided to liberate me from this toddler. Thanks to you I can go back to my shift without disturbance. Here, take this as a gift for helping a Renegade in need."</text>
            <autoReward level="MED">weapon</autoReward>
            <choice>
                <text>Continue...</text>
                <event load="MORALITY_REMOVE_EMV_RENEGADES_GENERAL"/>
            </choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
</event>

<event name="EMV_DEADCREW_UNION_UNAUTHORIZED">
    <text>The civilian vessel has been vanquished. You doubt that this would look good on your record though, plenty of scrap to be earned on the other hand..</text>
	<autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
    <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Continue...</text>
        <event>
            <text>The Renegade vessel hails you once more. "About time someone decided to liberate me from this toddler. Thanks to you I can go back to my shift without disturbance. Here, take this as a gift for helping a Renegade in need."</text>
            <autoReward level="MED">weapon</autoReward>
            <choice>
                <text>Continue...</text>
                <event load="MORALITY_REMOVE_EMV_RENEGADES_GENERAL"/>
            </choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
</event>

<event name="EMV_DEFEAT_GUARD_UNAUTHORIZED">
    <text>Despite whatever consequences that will come out of this, you eliminate the Renegade vessel in order to protect the Union vessel.</text>
	<autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
    <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Continue...</text>
        <event>
            <text>As you scrap the ship, you are hailed by the Union vessel. "I- I'm not sure what to say but, thank you. I didn't want this to end in bloodshed but he wouldn't let it go. I don't think it'll end well for you but, take this. Good luck.</text>
            <autoReward level="MED">stuff</autoReward>
            <choice>
                <text>Continue...</text>
                <event load="MORALITY_REMOVE_UNION"/>
            </choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
</event>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_TRESPASSERS"> <!-- tadaaah wawawawawa -->
	<preventQuest/>
	<beaconType text="[style[color:ffffff]]TRESPASSER[[/style]]" global="true">
		<color r="30" g="54" b="104" a="1"/>
		<unvisitedTooltip>Location of a Trespasser.</unvisitedTooltip>
		<visitedTooltip>Explored location. Nothing left of interest.</visitedTooltip>
	</beaconType>
    <text>According to the broadcasts, there's a trespasser inbound to here.. And right on cue, here they come!</text>
    <choice>
      <text>Continue...</text>
      <event load="MV_TRAVELER"/>
    </choice>
</event>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_RETIREMENT"> <!-- :3 -->
    <text>A Renegade stops you in your path and requests one thing from you. "Hey there, hotshot. Take this, I won't be needing me ship no more. Gonna live in me ol' home till I die and become one with the dust, be seeing ya." For whatever reason, the Renegade gives you his ship to scrap, you won't say no to free stuff.</text>
    <autoReward level="LOW">stuff</autoReward>
    <choice>
        <text>Do something onboard the ship.</text>
        <event load="STORAGE_CHECK"/>
    </choice>
    <choice>
        <text>Do nothing.</text>
        <event/>
    </choice>
</event>
<event name="EMV_MVPMC_BADASSITUDE" unique="true">
    <text>Your radio auto tunes to a televised signal about some sort of ancient vault that lurks within the universe, looking for vault hunters to open it. As you look into the offer, the broadcast suddenly cuts to a muscular man with a big moustache and sunglasses, calling it boring. "I'M TORQUE, AND I HAVE ONE QUESTION, AND ONE QUESTION ONLY. EXPLOSIONS????" As the guy says that, the signal flickers to a company logo with poorly edited in explosion effects. You can see a back and forth argument between two people on the screen, prompting you to cut it off. You notice that a random missile weapon is floating in space for some reason as well.</text>
    <weapon name="GIFTLIST_MISSILES"/>
    <choice>
        <text>Continue.</text>
        <event/>
    </choice>
</event>
<event name="EMV_MVPMC_CONSPIRACY" unique="true">
    <text>As soon as you jump into the system, your radio gets instantly blasted by incomprehensible gibberish of someone speaking about a "slug deepstate" and "ancient gods" that exist beyond our knowledge. He also blabbers about "something gilded" that only tests the mighiest people. You don't listen to it much because they get instantly vaporized by a Renegade ship to stop the broadcast. Some bits of scrap fly to your ship as a result of that though.</text>
    <autoReward level="LOW">stuff</autoReward>
    <choice>
         <text>Continue.</text>
        <event/>
    </choice>
</event>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_PROPAGANDA" unique="true">
    <text>Through your ship's radio, you detect a Rebel frequency broadcasting propaganda to attract the attention of Renegades. They also happen to talk about you, providing scrap for anyone that reports your location. You worry that this could give the fleet a solid reading of your location.</text>
    <choice>
        <text>Activate your radio and offer even bigger rewards.</text>
        <event>
            <text>You make your ship's channel public for anyone to listen to, broadcasting hefty rewards for anyone that intercepts the fleet pretending to be you. Much to the dismay of the rebel  broadcast, a Renegade takes your offer and scoops your scrap very quickly to go against the fleet headfirst. This should give you a good lead against the rebels.</text>
            <modifyPursuit amount="-2"/>
            <item_modify>
				<item type="scrap" min="-5" max="-10"/>
			</item_modify>
            <choice>
                <text>Continue.</text>
                <event/>
            </choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Try to intimidate the Rebels.</text>
        <event load="EMV_MVPMC_PROPAGANDA_INTIMIDATION"/>
    </choice>
    <choice>
        <text>Leave as fast as you can.</text>
        <event>
            <text>Even if your location gets compromised, you make haste with what you have and get out of there as soon as possible to avoid getting torn by the fleet's incoming ASB.</text>
        </event>
    </choice>
    <choice req="hacking" lvl="1">
        <text>(Hacking) Hijack the frequency.</text>
        <event>
            <text>You remotely hijack the rebels' frequency and start playing some... less than appropriate broadcasts for everyone to listen to. The rebels scramble to fix their "mishap" as they are approached by MVPMC officials and are told to leave the system. You also transmit false data to the fleet while you're at it.</text>
            <modifyPursuit amount="-2"/>
            <reveal_map/>
        </event>
    </choice>
</event>

<eventList name="EMV_MVPMC_PROPAGANDA_INTIMIDATION">
    <event load="EMV_MVPMC_PROPAGANDA_GOOD"/>
    <event load="EMV_MVPMC_PROPAGANDA_BAD"/>
</eventList>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_PROPAGANDA_GOOD">
    <text>You approach the rebels broadcasting the propaganda with your weapons armed and pointed at them. Their broadcast instantly comes to a halt and they apologise for the inconvenience while packing up to leave. You also extort some scrap out of them for the trouble.</text>
    <modifyPursuit amount="-1"/>
    <autoReward level="LOW">stuff</autoReward>
</event>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_PROPAGANDA_BAD">
    <text>As you approach the rebels with your weapons armed, you're less than pleased to notice an elite fighter coming to meet you in return! You are promptly hailed by the rebel captain. "So you're approaching me?!"</text>
	<ship load="SHIP_EMV_MVPMC_REBEL_ELITE" hostile="true"/>
    <choice>
        <text>I can't destroy you without getting closer!</text>
        <event load="COMBAT_CHECK"/>
    </choice>
</event>

<ship name="SHIP_EMV_MVPMC_REBEL_ELITE" auto_blueprint="LIST_SHIPS_REBEL_ELITE_FIGHT">
	<destroyed load="EMV_DEFEAT_REBEL_ELITE_PROPAGANDA"/>
	<deadCrew load="EMV_DEFEAT_REBEL_ELITE_PROPAGANDA"/>
	<crew>
		<crewMember type="LIST_CREW_REBEL_RANDOM" prop="0.5"/>
		<crewMember type="human_soldier" prop="0.5"/>
	</crew>
</ship>

<event name="EMV_DEFEAT_REBEL_ELITE_PROPAGANDA">
    <text>Despite the surprise attack from one of the Rebellion's Elite, they were still no match for your prowess. You move in to scrap their ship before facing the rebels broadcast station.</text>
	<autoReward level="MED">weapon</autoReward>
    <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Continue...</text>
        <event>
            <text>Alright alright you made your p-point! No more f-fleet, we happy here? Just do whatever you want that isn't killing us and take what you need! We're leaving!</text>
            <modifyPursuit amount="-1"/>
            <autoReward level="LOW">stuff</autoReward>
        </event>
    </choice>
</event>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_SHERIFF" unique="true">
    <ship load="SHIP_EMV_MVPMC_SHERIFF"/>
    <text>A "sheriff" looking guy hails you and requests your help as you enter the system. "Howdy there, Renegade. My name is Sheriff Wringer, I'm looking for this outlaw here around the sector, care to become a deputy of law?</text>
    <choice>
        <text>Sure, why not?</text>
        <event>
            <text>"Nice goin' there, pardner. There this rapscallion here who's been makin' some... wild moves. Just two days ago he put down four of my men, may they rest in peace. Return him to me, dead or alive." The sheriff gives you the last known location of the outlaw and you move to hunt them down.</text>
	        <quest event="EMV_MVPMC_SHERIFF_QUEST"/>
        </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
        <text>Not really, I'm too busy.</text>
        <event>
            <text>"Hmph, fair 'nuff. Kids these days forgot the honor and law..."" You distance yourself from the now disappointed sheriff and prepare to move on.</text>
            <choice>
                <text>Do something onboard the ship.</text>
                <event load="STORAGE_CHECK"/>
            </choice>
            <choice>
                <text>Do nothing..</text>
                <event/>
            </choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
        <text>Attack the sheriff.</text>
        <event>
            <ship hostile="true"/>
            <text>The Sheriff is surprised as you arm your weapons and aim towards their ship. You're promptly hailed by the Sheriff. "It's High Noon..." You're confused by how they're keeping track of time, considering how meaningless "noon" is in this situation.</text>
            <choice>
                <text>Continue...</text>
                <event load="MORALITY_UPDATE_EMV_RENEGADES_FIGHT"/>
            </choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
</event>

<ship name="SHIP_EMV_MVPMC_SHERIFF" auto_blueprint="MT_FEDERATION_3">
	<destroyed load="EMV_DEFEAT_SHERIFF_DESTROYED"/> <!-- Gotta write that -->
	<deadCrew load="EMV_DEFEAT_SHERIFF_CREWKILL"/> <!-- same with this-->
</ship>

<event name="EMV_DEFEAT_SHERIFF_DESTROYED">
    <text>You have defeated the Sheriff Wringer. You hastily scrap up his ship before any of his deputies arrive to avenge him for your hubris. Despite the thrill, you doubt anyone will give you safe haven.</text>
	<autoReward level="HIGH">weapon</autoReward>
    <choice>
        <text>Continue...</text>
        <event load="MORALITY_UPDATE_EMV_RENEGADES_GENERAL"/>
    </choice>
</event>

<event name="EMV_DEFEAT_SHERIFF_CREWKILL">
    <text>You have defeated the Sheriff Wringer. You hastily scrap up his ship before any of his deputies arrive to avenge him for your hubris. Despite the thrill, you doubt anyone will give you safe haven.</text>
	<autoReward level="HIGH">weapon</autoReward>
    <choice>
        <text>Continue...</text>
        <event load="MORALITY_UPDATE_EMV_RENEGADES_GENERAL"/>
    </choice>
</event>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_SHERIFF_QUEST">
	<beaconType id="map_icon_quest" global="true">
		<color r="69" g="168" b="235" a="1"/>
		<unvisitedTooltip>A sheriff has informed you of a high value target here.</unvisitedTooltip>
	</beaconType>
    <ship load="SHIP_EMV_SHERIFF_PIRATE"/>
    <text>You track down one of the most wanted criminals as told by the Sheriff. To your surprise, they're no ordinary fresh-outta-school pirate, but a seasoned one, piloting a one of a kind ship. This is truly a noble duel between good and evil.</text>
    <choice>
        <text>It's High Noon, scumbag.</text>
        <event>
            <text>"Huh, wuh? Noon? What are you talking abou- Oh crap! Boys, we've got trouble here!" The pirate is caught off guard by your sudden appearance and moves in to attack!</text>
            <ship hostile="true"/>
            <choice>
                <text>Continue...</text>
                <event load="COMBAT_CHECK"/>
            </choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
        <text>Bolt the hell out.</text>
        <event>
            <text>You decide that honors and manners aren't convenient when there is risk on your mission, you leave the job for someone else.</text>
            <choice>
                <text>Do something onboard the ship.</text>
                <event load="STORAGE_CHECK"/>
            </choice>
            <choice>
                <text>Do nothing..</text>
                <event/>
            </choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
</event>

<ship name="SHIP_EMV_SHERIFF_PIRATE" auto_blueprint="LIST_SHIPS_PIRATE_ELITE_ALL">
	<escape  chance="0.3" min="3" max="4" load="ESCAPE_PIRATE"/>
	<gotaway load="GOTAWAY_PIRATE"/>
	<destroyed load="EMV_SHERIFF_PIRATE_DESTROY"/>
	<deadCrew load="EMV_SHERIFF_PIRATE_CREWKILL"/>
</ship>

<event name="EMV_SHERIFF_PIRATE_CREWKILL">
    <text>You manage to empty the pirate ship of its crew and corner the pirate captain into his cabin. "Well, end of the line for me then. It was fun while it lasted, but I guess my time has come." You radio the Sheriff, informing him that the pirate captain is in your custody. "Well well, that's a pleasant surprise to hear. Bring him in to the nearest colony, I'll race ya there and prepare for his hanging by noon. Well done, kiddo." You're confused about how the Sheriff can keep track of time in space, but that doesn't matter now since you are given the coordinates for the nearest colony to hand over the pirate to.</text>
    <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
    <quest event="EMV_SHERIFF_FINALE"/>
</event>

<event name="EMV_SHERIFF_PIRATE_DESTROY">
    <text>You watch as the pirate criminal's ship goes up into flames, with its captain's charred hat getting flung into space. You radio the Sheriff, notifying him of your job. "Well done, pardner. Great to know that the young generation still has honors these days. See ya round, cowboy."</text>
    <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
    <choice>
        <text>Continue...</text>
        <event load="MORALITY_REMOVE_EMV_RENEGADES_GENERAL"/>
    </choice>
</event>


<event name="EMV_SHERIFF_FINALE">
	<beaconType id="map_icon_quest" global="true">
		<color r="69" g="168" b="235" a="1"/>
		<unvisitedTooltip>The sheriff has rewards for you here.</unvisitedTooltip>
	</beaconType>
    <text>You finally get to the colony, hoping that it's noon by the Sheriff's standards. He hails you as you watch the Sheriff's deputies take the pirate captain away. "Well done. cowboy. And right on glaring light of a High Noon. Say, the families of the dead men who were murdered by this lowlife are willing to thank you in their own way for bringing the scum to justice. Head on to the nearest armory and take whatever tickles your fancy. I'll see ya around, cowboy."</text>
    <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Continue...</text>
        <event>
            <text>You are hastily rushed into an armory belonging to the colony and given the keys for it to take whatever you want on your trip. You take whatever suits you and make sure the town isn't completely defenseless. You bid farewell as you watch the pirate captain gunned down by a firing squad from a distance.</text>
            <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
            <weapon name="EMV_RENEGADE_STORE_CURATED"/>
            <choice>
                <text>Continue...</text>
                <event load="MORALITY_REMOVE_EMV_RENEGADES_GENERAL"/>
            </choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
</event>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_SCRAPYARD" unique="true">
    <text>Through the corner of your eye, you spot a dozen fleet sized Renegade vessels hauling cargo towards a deserted planet. You proceed towards the station they came from and inquire about what they're hauling. "Oh, the planet? It's just a big abandoned landfill for any passing Renegade ship. We're guarding it to avoid any garbage feeders from causing nuisance over there."</text>
    <choice>
        <text>Ask if you can salvage some of the waste down there.</text>
        <event>
            <text>The Renegade station owner discusses this with fellow Renegades before turning back to you. "Alright, you can go there, as long as you pay us a heap of scrap. Anything that happens down there is your responsibility, we won't babysit you."</text>
            <choice>
                <text>Offer some scrap.</text>
                <event>
                    <text>You offer the scrap and get reminded about the risks of this salvage operation. As you descend down, your ship is drenched in putrid stench and you can see rusted particles flying through the air. You can only search for a while before this poses a true threat for you and your crew.</text>
                    <item_modify>
                        <item type="scrap" min="-10" max="-15"/>
                    </item_modify>
                    <choice hidden="true">
                        <text>Look for anything.</text>
                        <event load="EMV_MVPMC_SCRAPYARD_OUTCOME"/>
                    </choice>
                    <choice hidden="true" req="SCRAP_COLLECTOR">
                        <text>(Scrap arm) Try to pull some stuff.</text>
                        <event load="EMV_MVPMC_SCRAPYARD_ARM"/>
                    </choice>
                </event>
            </choice>
            <choice>
                <text>Refuse and leave.</text>
                <event>
                    <text>You politely refuse due to the lack of insurance in this salvage operation, not to mention the price. You depart from the station and prepare to move on.</text>
                    <choice>
                        <text>Do something onboard the ship.</text>
                        <event load="STORAGE_CHECK"/>
                    </choice>
                    <choice>
                        <text>Do nothing..</text>
                        <event/>
                    </choice>                    
                </event>
            </choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
        <text>Leave without inquiring further.</text>
        <event>
            <text>You have no interest in a glorified mega-sized junkyard. The station bids you farewell, you notice you still have time to do something as you prepare to move on.</text>
            <choice>
                <text>Do something onboard the ship.</text>
                <event load="STORAGE_CHECK"/>
            </choice>
            <choice>
                <text>Do nothing..</text>
                <event/>
            </choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
</event>

<eventList name="EMV_MVPMC_SCRAPYARD_OUTCOME">
    <event load="EMV_MVPMC_SCRAPYARD_SCRAP"/>
    <event load="EMV_MVPMC_SCRAPYARD_SUPPLIES"/>
    <event load="EMV_MVPMC_SCRAPYARD_WEAPON"/>
    <event load="EMV_MVPMC_SCRAPYARD_DRONE"/>
    <event load="EMV_MVPMC_SCRAPYARD_AUGMENT"/>
    <event load="EMV_MVPMC_SCRAPYARD_MAPINFO"/>
</eventList>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_SCRAPYARD_SCRAP">
    <text>You pull out a great heap of scrap from the hull of a destroyed ship. For some reason the scrap is littered with glowing dust all over it, but you don't pay it mind as you haul it back to the ship.</text>
    <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
</event>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_SCRAPYARD_SUPPLIES">
    <text>You unearth boxes of supplies. You find a handful of leftovers in those boxes, but it's a great find nonetheless.</text>
    <autoReward level="HIGH">stuff</autoReward>
</event>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_SCRAPYARD_WEAPON">
    <text>As you are looking for something of worth, your crew alert you of a never opened weapons crate! You bring it on the ship and uncover this great find.</text>
    <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
    <weapon name="LIST_EMV_SCRAPYARD_WEAPONS"/>
</event>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_SCRAPYARD_DRONE">
    <text>A crewmember manages to find schematics for a drone design inside of a box. They bring it back to the ship, ready to be used.</text>
    <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
    <drone name="GIFTLIST_COMBAT_DRONES"/>
</event>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_SCRAPYARD_AUGMENT">
    <text>Inside the shell of a destroyed ship, you find an augment that belonged to said ship. You take it off of the ship to use it on yours.</text>
    <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
    <augment name="GIFTLIST_AUGMENT_COMBAT"/>
</event>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_SCRAPYARD_MAPINFO">
    <text>You don't find anything of worth sadly, however; a crew member brings a drive full of coordinates and map readings. It's not a lot, but navigating your way is good enough.</text>
    <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
    <reveal_map/>
</event>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_SCRAPYARD_ARM">
    <text>You decide that it's not worth risking your crew's life over this and opt out to use the scrap arm to pull of scrap back to the ship. You come up with a decent haul through that.</text>
    <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
</event>


<event name="EMV_MVPMC_CONVOY">
	<customFleet right="false" firing="false" autoDarkening="true">EMV_CUSTOM_FLEET_MVPMC</customFleet>
    <text>As soon as you jump into the system, you detect another multiversal drive reading close to your location! You worry that it's a hunter of some sort, but it appears to be a large ship convoy belonging to your fellow Renegades. You ease up a bit before you go back to your post.</text>
    <choice>
        <text>Do something onboard the ship.</text>
        <event load="STORAGE_CHECK"/>
    </choice>
    <choice>
        <text>Do nothing..</text>
        <event/>
    </choice>
</event>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_ENVY" unique="true">
    <text>From the corner of your eye, you hear up a lot of chatter coming from a few ships. "Hell yeah boys! We're gonna be so rich! SO RICH! That vault will keep us afloat forever and ever! Let's waste no time, c'mon!!" You envy their free time, and begin preparing to follow them before noticing the "vault" they're after is almost definitely somewhere in the rebel fleet. You gear up to move instead.</text>
    <choice>
        <text>Do something onboard the ship.</text>
        <event load="STORAGE_CHECK"/>
    </choice>
    <choice>
        <text>Do nothing..</text>
        <event/>
    </choice>
</event>


<event name="EMV_MVPMC_PREY" unique="true">
    <ship load="SHIP_EMV_PSYCHOTIC_RENEGADE"/>
    <text>A torn down vessel intercepts you, hailing you repeatedly. "Please help us I'm begging you! We are being chased by an insane freak who has been tailing us and tearing us apart! We'll give you anything just protect us from that psycho-" Before the captain finishes their sentence, you are hailed by the pursuer. "Well, looks like my hunt is nothing short of eventful. Tell ya what, you let go of that little bunny, and I might give you a little somethin' somethin'. How does that sound for you, fellow hunter?</text>
    <choice>
        <text>Accept the bribe.</text>
        <event>
            <text>You decide to cut comms with the prey and move towards the Renegade ship. They exchange you some of the supplies before wishing you good luck. From the corner of your eye, you can see as the hunted ship gets torn apart by the Renegade. As impressive as that looked, you don't want to linger around any longer.</text>
            <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
        </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
        <text>Protect the ship.</text>
        <event>
            <text>You move into a protective stance and arm your weapons. The Renegade doesn't take that lightly and can barely hide their annoyance with a smile. "Well, can't say no to removing more pest from space!" You prepare to fight!</text>
            <ship hostile="true"/>
            <choice>
                <text>Continue...</text>
                <event load="MORALITY_UPDATE_EMV_RENEGADES_FIGHT"/>
            </choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
    <choice hidden="true" req="weapons" lvl="5">
        <text>(Upg. Weapons) How about no?</text>
        <event>
            <text>You show the Renegade that you aren't messing around when it comes to preserving life. They take note of your weaponry and slowly back off. "Okay uhhh, must've been the wind. Pack it up boys! We're leaving!" They leave the system, giving you enough time to check on the hunted once more.

"I cannot express my gratitude enough for your help. You've saved so many lives on board and we are forever grateful for your assistance. Please take this and take care."</text>
            <autoReward level="HIGH">weapon</autoReward>
        </event>
    </choice>
</event>


<ship name="SHIP_EMV_PSYCHOTIC_RENEGADE" auto_blueprint="LIST_MULTIVERSE_TRAVELERS">
    <destroyed load="EMV_PSYCHOTIC_DESTROY"/>
    <deadCrew load="EMV_PSYCHOTIC_CREWKILL"/>
</ship>

<event name="EMV_PSYCHOTIC_DESTROY">
    <text>The Renegade vessel has been finally defeated. You scrap the ship before checking on the hunted once more.</text>
    <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
    <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Continue...</text>
        <event>
            <text>The torn up ship hails you. "I cannot express my gratitude enough for your help. You've saved so many lives on board and we are forever grateful for your assistance. Please take this and take care."</text>
            <autoReward level="HIGH">weapon</autoReward>
        </event>
    </choice>
</event>

<event name="EMV_PSYCHOTIC_CREWKILL">
    <text>The Renegade vessel has been finally defeated. You scrap the ship before checking on the hunted once more.</text>
    <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
    <choice hidden="true">
        <text>Continue...</text>
        <event>
            <text>The torn up ship hails you. "I cannot express my gratitude enough for your help. You've saved so many lives on board and we are forever grateful for your assistance. Please take this and take care."</text>
            <autoReward level="HIGH">weapon</autoReward>
        </event>
    </choice>
</event>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_STORE_SERVICE" unique="true">
	<preventQuest/>
	<beaconType id="map_icon_hostilestore" global="false">
		<color r="215" g="175" b="175" a="1"/>
	</beaconType>
    <ship load="EMV_MVPMC_STORE_REBEL"/>
    <text>You notice that an MV intruder is holding a store hostage. You receive a hail from the store owner begging for help. "Please help us outta here! This lunatic has been drunkenly shouting Rebel schtick ever since we denied him service, you've got to put him out of his sad misery!</text>
    <choice>
        <text>Rescue the store.</text>
        <event>
            <text>You move in protect the store from the miserable Rebel captain who has been denied service. "Youuuu Renegade lackeys will- hick be crus-crused!! under the might of- hick -the Rebellionnnnnn!"</text>
            <ship hostile="true"/>
            <choice>
                <text>Continue...</text>
                <event load="COMBAT_CHECK"/>
            </choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
    <choice>
        <text>Leave them to themselves.</text>
        <event>
            <text>You decide that whatever is going on is none of your business as you tune the store owner who's fumbling at reading Renegade codes of conduct out. You prepare to move on.</text>
            <choice>
                <text>Do something onboard the ship.</text>
                <event load="STORAGE_CHECK"/>
            </choice>
            <choice>
                <text>Do nothing..</text>
                <event/>
            </choice>            
        </event>
    </choice>
</event>

<ship name="EMV_MVPMC_STORE_REBEL" auto_blueprint="LIST_SHIPS_MULTIVERSE">
	<destroyed load="EMV_MVPMC_STORE_REBEL_DESTROYED"/>
	<deadCrew load="EMV_MVPMC_STORE_REBEL_CREWKILL"/>
</ship>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_STORE_REBEL_DESTROYED">
    <text>As you move in to the store and scrap the ship, your mind drifts into trying to remember a quote about burials and soup cans, glues and hell. You forget about it until you get something from the store.</text>
    <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
    <choice>
        <text>Continue...</text>
        <event>
            <text>The store owner ushers you into the store where you can select from a specially curated list. "Thank you for your help there. Usually we have to extort an entry fee from you, but what the hell, you saved us and that's better than a few extra bits of scrap! The store is all for you, my friend."</text>
			<store>EMV_RENEGADE_STORE</store>
			<choice>
				<text>Do something onboard the ship.</text>
				<event load="STORAGE_CHECK"/>
			</choice>
			<choice>
				<text>Do nothing.</text>
				<event/>
			</choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
</event>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_STORE_REBEL_CREWKILL">
    <text>As you move in to the store and scrap the ship, your mind drifts into trying to remember a quote about burials and soup cans, glues and hell. You forget about it until you get something from the store.</text>
    <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
    <choice>
        <text>Continue...</text>
        <event>
            <text>The store owner ushers you into the store where you can select from a specially curated list. "Thank you for your help there. Usually we have to extort an entry fee from you, but what the hell, you saved us and that's better than a few extra bits of scrap! The store is all for you, my friend."</text>
			<store>EMV_RENEGADE_STORE</store>
			<choice>
				<text>Do something onboard the ship.</text>
				<event load="STORAGE_CHECK"/>
			</choice>
			<choice>
				<text>Do nothing.</text>
				<event/>
			</choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
</event>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_FREIGHTER" unique="true">
    <text>As soon as you jump into the beacon, you barely dodge a massive container floating in space. As soon as you get your bearings, you realise you're amidst a freighter's wreckage. You don't think whoever caused this left anything of worth, but you do your best to pull some loose scrap off.</text>
    <customFleet right="false" firing="false" autoDarkening="true">EMV_CUSTOM_FLEET_MVPMC_WRECK</customFleet>
    <autoReward level="LOW">standard</autoReward>
    <choice req="LIST_CREW_LANIUS">
        <text>(Lanius) Have your Lanius extract more scrap.</text>
        <event>
            <text>You order your lanius crew to get into the wreckage and get some more scrap. It doesn't take long for them to get a modest heap for you to make use of.</text>
            <autoReward level="MED">standard</autoReward>
        </event>
    </choice>
    <choice req="SCRAP_COLLECTOR">
        <text>(Scrap arm) Try to get more scrap.</text>
        <event>
            <text>You use the scrap arm on your ship to get a bit more scrap from the tougher parts of the ship. The arm works its wonders and you get more scrap out of the wreck and leave it at that.</text>
            <autoReward level="HIGH">standard</autoReward>
        </event>
    </choice>
	<choice>
		<text>Do something onboard the ship.</text>
		<event load="STORAGE_CHECK"/>
	</choice>
	<choice>
		<text>Do nothing.</text>
		<event/>
	</choice>
</event>

<event name="EMV_MVPMC_GRADUATION">
    <text>You notice some sort of celebration happening out in the distance. Upon closer inspection, you are informed that it's a Renegade graduation party and anyone can attend to it. You stay for a bit and chat to the new Renegade about how stuff works and how Renegade life is. They appreciate your advice and give you a weapon from their stock as an appreciation.</text>
    <autoReward level="LOW">weapon</autoReward>
</event>

<event name="EMV_ROGUE_CAMP_SEARCH" unique="true">
    <text>As soon as you enter the system, your ship's sensors detect faint unusual signals coming from a nearby place. However, you don't seem to be able to find it with your naked eye, nor does it appear on the radar.</text>
    <choice>
        <text>Try to look for the origin of the signals.</text>
        <event load="EMV_ROGUE_CAMP_OUTCOMES"/>
    </choice>
    <choice req="sensors" lvl="2">
        <text>(Upg. Sensors) Overclock your sensors.</text>
        <event load="EMV_ROGUE_CAMP_SENSORS_GOOD"/>
    </choice>
    <choice req="ADV_SCANNERS">
        <text>(Long-Ranged Scanners) Overclock your sensors.</text>
        <event load="EMV_ROGUE_CAMP_SENSORS_GOOD"/>
    </choice>
    <choice>
        <text>Leave it as is.</text>
        <event>
            <text>You have no interest in a wild goose chase involving unknown signals. You leave them mystery as is and get going.</text>
            <choice>
                <text>Do something onboard the ship.</text>
                <event load="STORAGE_CHECK"/>
            </choice>
            <choice>
                <text>Do nothing.</text>
                <event/>
            </choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
</event>

<eventList name="EMV_ROGUE_CAMP_OUTCOMES">
    <event load="EMV_ROGUE_CAMP_SENSORS_BAD"/>
    <event load="EMV_ROGUE_CAMP_SENSORS_BAD"/>
    <event load="EMV_ROGUE_CAMP_SENSORS_BAD"/>
    <event load="EMV_ROGUE_CAMP_SENSORS_GOOD"/>
</eventList>

<event name="EMV_ROGUE_CAMP_SENSORS_BAD">
    <text>You try your best at finding the signal, but no matter how hard you try, your sensors aren't strong enough to find it and it flickers out of the map.</text>
    <choice>
        <text>Do something onboard the ship.</text>
        <event load="STORAGE_CHECK"/>
    </choice>
    <choice>
        <text>Do nothing.</text>
        <event/>
    </choice>
</event>

<event name="EMV_ROGUE_CAMP_SENSORS_GOOD">
    <text>You maximize your sensor's detection range to try and find the source of the signal. Luckily, they are strong enough to exactly pinpoint the location of the nearby settlement that broadcasted the signal.</text>
    <choice>
        <text>Approach the settlement.</text>
        <event load="EMV_ROGUE_CAMP"/>
    </choice>
    <choice>
        <text>Leave.</text>
        <event>
            <text>If there is one thing you should take note of, it's that hidden settlements like these scream for an unaware ship to dock there and get killed in. You leave as soon as possible.</text>
            <choice>
                <text>Do something onboard the ship.</text>
                <event load="STORAGE_CHECK"/>
            </choice>
            <choice>
                <text>Do nothing.</text>
                <event/>
            </choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
</event>

<event name="EMV_ROGUE_CAMP">
    <text>Cautiously docking there, you can't help but notice that the settlement was a former Rebel hideout. Fading orange palette, burnt MFK Eagles, scattered Ace helmets on the very ground. The tense feeling drenches your mind in worries, and the sudden appearance of a glowing blue hue from the darkness doesn't make it any better.</text>
    <choice>
        <text>Identify Yourself.</text>
        <event>
            <text>You announce your presence to the residents of the settlement. One by one, the glowing lights appear more and more abundant, outnumbering you and your crew. "So... another unaware rebel, how intriguing. Maybe we are not as hidden as we thought we were. Prepare to die and follow your rotten brethren!"</text>
            <choice>
                <text>Wait! I'm not with the Rebellion!</text>
                <event>
                    <text>As soon as those word are muttered, the mysterious figures stop in their position and come to the light and reveal themselves. "You're not... a Rebel? Then what are you? How did you find us here?"</text>
                    <choice>
                        <text>We are en route to Node 17.</text>
                        <event>
                            <text>"Node 17... the bane of... let's leave that as a story for another day. Why do you want to go there, then?"</text>
                            <choice>
                                <text>To save the Federation.</text>
                                <event>
                                    <text>"Huh, okay. Leave." You take note of the dozens of armed blasters aimed towards you and your crew as soon as you stated your intentions, prompting you to head back and never touch down on the settlement again."</text>
                                	<boarders min="2" max="3" class="emv_mv_human_mercenary"/>
                                </event>
                            </choice>
                            <choice hidden="true">
                                <text>To get some scrap.</text>
                                <event>
                                    <text>"Well then, at least you're working for yourself here. Maybe seeing the Rebels fall this time will be nothing short of entertainment. Have this and good luck." You notice that a few engineers head towards your ship and upgrade its weapons systems! You bid the settlement farewell as they wish you good luck.</text>
                                    <upgrade amount="1" system="weapons"/>
                                </event>
                            </choice>
                            <choice>
                                <text>Looking for fun.</text>
                                <event>
                                    <text>"A thrill seeker? That's... hardly surprising, but not that it makes an issue for me. Better get there quickly then. The settlement wishes you good luck on your journey, and order some of their engineers to upgrade your engines to get to your goal quickly. You bid them farewell and get going."</text>
                                    <upgrade amount="1" system="engines"/>
                                </event>
                            </choice>
                            <choice hidden="true" req="human_mfk">
                                <text>(MFK Ace) The Rebellion is weak and in its darkest hours. We are finishing the job.</text>
                                <event>
                                    <text>Your Ace makes and appearance and faces one of the settlers, explaining that the Rebels are nothing short of deranged lunatics who have got too greedy with power and are in a spiraling state, soon to crash down harder than thunder. The leader of the settlement approaches you and shakes your hand before sending one of his men with you. "An enemy of my enemy is a friend. One of my elites will be with you on this trip. Give them hell, kid."</text>
                                    <crewMember amount="1" class="EMV_LIST_CREW_ROGUE_GIFT"/>
                                    <autoReward level="HIGH">stuff</autoReward>
                                </event>
                            </choice>
                            <choice hidden="true" req="EMV_LIST_CREW_ROGUE">
                                <text>(Rogue crew) We request help from you, brother.</text>
                                <event>
                                    <text>As soon as you present your Rogue crew, the mysterious figure stands in a saluting position and offers all the help they could. "Bound to no flag and no code, we serve the Old Glory!" You are rushed back to the ship to see engineers modifying it and applying the best upgrades on it, as well as a loyal powerful crewmember wishing to join your mission! You say your goodbyes and head onwards.</text>
                                    <crewMember amount="1" class="EMV_LIST_CREW_ROGUE_GIFT" pilot="1"/>
                                    <upgrade amount="1" system="weapons"/>
                                    <weapon name="LASER_BURST_2"/>
                                </event>
                            </choice>
                        </event>
                    </choice>
                    <choice hidden="true">
                        <text>We're more or less like you, flagless and without alleigance!</text>
                        <event>
                            <text>"Another fellow, I see. Well, best we can do is give you a fair bit of supplies and wish you good luck. Don't tell anyone about this." The mysterious group hands you a cache of supplies and wish you good luck before reiterating that you tell no one about this. You leave the settlement, wondering about the strangers you saw.</text>
                            <autoReward level="HIGH">stuff</autoReward>
                        </event>
                    </choice>
                    <choice>
                        <text>Why does it matter to you?</text>
                        <event>
                            <text>"Well, that answers my question. We have an intruder! Open fire!" As soon as that figure shouts the order, a dozen lasers rain on you and your crew! Thankfully, you make back to your ship in one piece, but you also notice teleportation signatures on your ship!"</text>
                            <boarders min="2" max="3" class="emv_mv_human_mercenary"/>
                            <environment type="PDS" target="player"/>
                        </event>
                    </choice>
                </event>
            </choice>
        </event>
    </choice>
</event>




<event name="FINISH_BEACON_MVPMC">
	<text id="finish_beacon"/>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Explore.</text>
		<event load="EXIT_FILLER_LIST"/>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Do something onboard the ship.</text>
		<event load="STORAGE_CHECK"/>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Do nothing.</text>
		<event/>
	</choice>
</event>

<event name="FINISH_BEACON_FLEET_MVPMC">
	<revisitEvent>FINISH_BEACON_FLEET_MVPMC</revisitEvent>
	<customFleet right="true" firing="false" autoDarkening="true">EMV_CUSTOM_FLEET_MVPMC</customFleet>
	<customFleet right="false" firing="true" autoDarkening="false">CUSTOM_FLEET_REBEL</customFleet>
	<text>You've found the exit beacon, but the Rebels have already arrived, and an Elite is dispatched to track you! The MVPMC forces are retaliating, but you must still jump as soon as possible to the next sector.</text>
	<variable name="loc_dives" op="add" val="1"/>
	<ship load="SHIP_REBEL_FLEET" hostile="true"/>
	<fleet>rebel</fleet>
	<environment type="PDS" target="all"/>
	<noASBPlanet/>
	<choice hidden="true">
		<text>Continue...</text>
		<event load="COMBAT_CHECK"/>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true" req="engines" lvl="6">
		<text>(Adv. Engines) Try to escape the Elite.</text>
		<event load="FLEET_ESCAPE"/>
	</choice>
	<choice hidden="true" req="LIST_CREW_JERRY">
		<text>(Jerry) "Hello!"</text>
		<event>
			<text load="TEXT_ENCOUNTER_REBEL_JERRY_HELLO"/>
			<ship hostile="false"/> 
		</event>
	</choice>
</event>